Matt Wilson

Front End Developer

About me

After several years working for one of the country's leading media companies I'm now looking for an exciting new opportunity which will allow me to apply my knowledge and skills. I'm keen to work more with emerging technologies and techniques. I'm enthusiastic about my work and pride myself on attention to detail.

Experience

Sep 2014 - Dec 2016 UI Developer at Immediate Media Co.

Part of an agile scrum team responsible for the Radio Times website. Tasked with making the site fully responsive and accessible across all devices. Primary developer responsible for the modernisation of the TV listings web app. Helped to introduce front end coding standards and the use of linting tools. Setup build tools using Gulp & Webpack. Worked extensively on integrating third-party APIs. Researched and implemented unit tests using Jasmine. Regularly participated in company hackathons designed to encourage innovation.

*Jun 2012 - Apr 2014*Web Developer at Digital Trip Ltd.

Responsible for delivering both white-label & bespoke websites to a large number of clients in the travel industry. Created a number of new modules for the company's in-house CMS. Assisted in the development of the company's CSS style guide, for use across their entire product range. Integrated multi-lingual and multi-currency functionality. Direct technical support for clients.

Aug 2010 - Aug 2011 Junior Software Developer/Intern at PokerStars.

Assisted in the maintenance of the company's web based reporting suite. Implemented improved navigation options across the system. Prototyped an account tracking system for the Treasury Department. Worked closely with the IT Security Department to manage access privileges across the system.

Skills & Competencies

HTML5, CSS3

JavaScript, ES2015

SASS

CSS methodologies (BEM, SMACSS, ITCSS)

Babel, Gulp, Webpack

iQuery

Node & NPM

Handlebars.js

Bootstrap

Jasmine test framework

Mocha/Chai

Basic React knowledge

ASP.NET MVC

PHP

Vagrant

Google products (Tag Manager, Publisher Tag, Analytics)

Understanding of SEO & accessibility (ARIA)

Facebook SDK and other social network integrations

Git version control

Education

2012

BSc(Hons) Computing from Bournemouth University Awarded 2:1

2005

A-Levels from Castle Rushen High School Computing, Art Graphics & Product Design

References

Available on request.